（メイ）な…　何なの　あれ！？
W-What is that?
（綱手）カツユ！
Katsuyu!
（カツユ）はい。
私が　すべて説明します。
Yes, ma'am!
I shall explain everything!
（サイ）大丈夫かい？　サクラ。
（サクラ）うん。
Are you all right, Sakura...?
（カツユ）あともう少しで
五影様たちが…。
Yeah...
The Five Kage will
be here shortly.
（いの）シカマル！
（チョウジ）シカマル！
Shikamaru!
（シカマル）ハァハァ…　ハァ…。
（キバ）おい！　おい！
やべぇじゃねえかよ！
Hey!
Hey, he looks real bad!
カツユ様
すぐに遠隔治療に入ります！
Lady Katsuyu!
Let's begin Distance Healing
immediately!
それは　ムリです。
That's not possible.
（サクラ）なんでです！？
Why?!
小さくなって皆様についていた
私の分裂体のチャクラまで→
Even my mini fragments attached
to everyone have been drained...
すべて吸収されて
死んでしまいました。
They have lost their chakra
and died.
そんな…。
That's...
（カツユ）つまり
皆様も私の分裂体と同じです。
In other words...
Everyone is in the same state
as my fragments.
《ハァ…　親父　すまねぇ。
Sorry, Dad...
どうやらすぐに
そっちに行きそうだ…》
Looks like I'll be right
on your heels...
（チョウジ）シカマル！
Shikamaru!
《すまねぇ　母ちゃん…》
Sorry... Mom...
シカマル！
（いの）サクラ！
Shikamaru!
Sakura!
((どうせ死ぬなら　何もしないより
自分なりに戦って死ぬ！))
If we're going to die anyway,
we might as well go down fighting
to the best of our abilities!
これじゃ…　こんなんじゃ…。
But... at this rate...
ハァ…　ハァ…。
（サクラ）戦う前に
死んじゃうじゃない！
... we'll all die before
we even get to fight!
Ready, set, go, we step over the goal line
isse nou se de fumikomu gourain
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
We look back as we pass the line, and it's already gone
issen koete furikaeruto mou nai
Still, we don't know anything at all
bokura wa nanimo nanimo mada shiranu
Fiercely, fiercely we move on
udatte udatte udatteku
Drenched in glistening sweat
kirameku ase ga koboreru no sa
There probably were a lot of things we didn't remember
oboetenai koto mo takusan atta darou
Everyone was just a silhouette
daremo kare mo shiruetto
Let's become adults,
daiji ni shitai mono motte otona ni naru nda
holding on to things we want to cherish
And let's keep on protecting them at all times
donna toki mo hanasazu ni mamori tsudzukeyou
Then someday...
soshitara itsu no hi ni ka
We'll be able to laugh at it all
nanimo kamo o waraerusa
Like the light and nimble dancing
hirari to hirari to matteru
Of leaves taking flight
konoha ga tonde yuku
A Shinobi's Dream
（オビト）忍は終わりだ。
Shinobi are done for.
もう続けることはない。
There's no need to keep going.
抵抗しないならば　殺しはしない。
If you don't resist, I won't kill you.
((そして　お前が対立するかぎり→
If you keep opposing us,
これから仲間も
そうやって次々いなくなる。
you'll continue to lose
your comrades one by one!
(お前を認める者が
存在しない世界だ))
This will become a world
where no one who
acknowledges you will exist!
後悔したくなくば
もう何もしないことだ。
Unless you want to
be filled with regret,
stop and do nothing
from here on out.
何もしなければ
助かるってことか？
If we don't do anything,
we'll be saved...?
そうだ　もう死に怯え
耐え忍ぶこともない。
Yes...
You don't have to fear death
or keep enduring anymore.
夢の中へ行ける。
You'll be entering a dream.
（柱間）諦めるな！
Do not give up!
幻術の中に落ちれば
死人も同然ぞ！
If you succumb to a genjutsu,
you're no different from being dead!
（ヒルゼン）この大樹は
オビトと密接に繋がっておるの。
This giant tree is closely
connected to Obito...
まるで　チャクラを引き抜く手足。
They're like limbs
that suck out chakra.
うかつには近づけぬ。
We can't approach carelessly.
（大蛇丸）ずいぶん弱腰ですね。
あなたらしくない。
Such words of weakness.
So very unlike you.
猿飛先生。
Sarutobi Sensei...
大蛇丸　遅かったではないか。
で　五影は？
Orochimaru...
You're late...
What of the Five Kage?
回復してあげたから→
I had them healed.
弱腰じゃなければ
ここへ来るでしょうね。
So as long as they don't chicken out,
they should be coming.
フフッ　皮肉を言うのは変わらんな。
As sarcastic as ever, I see.
（水月）待たせたね　重吾にサスケ。
Sorry I'm late, Jugo! Sasuke!
（重吾）来たか。
You're here...
しかし　近くで見ると
やっぱ大きいね！
This tree is huge
now that I see it up close.
この木　切り倒すのに
どんだけ時間かかるかな？
I wonder how long
it'll take to cut down?
（香燐）んなことは
どうでもいいんだよ！
Who cares about that?!
それより今は…。
What's important right now...
《サスケんとこに
今すぐ行って　ハグして→
... is to go over to Sasuke and
hug and lick him, damn it!
なめまわしてぇんだよ　この野郎》
連合忍者の回復だろ？　キミ。
Is to heal the Allied
Forces shinobi, right?
そ…　そうだよ！
わかって　この野郎じゃねぇか！
Y-Yeah! I know
that already, damn it!
《不機嫌そうね…》
He seems to be in a foul mood.
《どういうことだ？
What's going on?
あのつぼみが開花したとき
無限月読は完全となる。
When that bud blooms,
Infinite Tsukuyomi will be complete.
マダラは　そう言った。
That's what Madara said.
だが　これほどの忍の
チャクラを吸い取ってなお→
And yet, after depleting
the chakra of this many shinobi...
つぼみが開花する気配はない》
the bud shows no signs of blooming.
なら　あれは　いつ開く！？
So when is it going to bloom?
（マダラ）八尾と九尾の人柱力が
まだ生きてる…　わかるな？
The Eight and Nine Tails still live.
Do you get it?
《開花させ　術を完成させるには→
So the chakra of the Eight
and Nine Tails is essential
八尾と九尾のチャクラが
必要不可欠だったということか》
to complete the jutsu...
だが　少なからず　その２匹の→
However, if it contains even a small
amount of each of their chakra,
チャクラが入っていれば
問題にはならん。
it's fine.
つまり…
開花できないわけではない。
In other words,
it's not like it can't bloom.
開花にかかる時間が
問題になるだけだ。
All that is affected....
is how long it will take
to bloom.
タイムリミットは　あと約１５分。
There's about 15 minutes to go.
その間に　オビトを止め　入れ代わる。
In that time, I shall stop Obito
and switch places with him.
お前の仙人の力を利用してな。
Using your Sage Power.
《まずいのう…。
This is bad.
俺のオリジナルが聞いたことを
すべて連合の皆に伝えなくては》
Everything my original just heard
must be relayed to the Allied Force.
ここに山中一族の者はおるか？
Anyone here belong to
the Yamanaka Clan?!
はい！
心伝身の術は？
Here!
Can you do
the Mind Transmission Jutsu?!
あっ…　はい　できます！
Yes, I can, sir!
頼む。　皆へ　つなげてくれ。
Good! Please link me
to everyone here!
あの無限月読とやらについて
説明しておきたいことがある。
There are things I'd like to explain
about that giant tree,
and the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
《この感じ…》
This sensation...
おじい様！
Grandfather!
（柱間）おお…　綱か。
Ah! Is that you, Tsuna?
（オオノキ）この声
間違いないの　柱間殿。
This voice is unmistakably
Lord Hashirama's!
（いの）はぁ…　五影様たちも→
This means the Five Kage
are close enough
私の術の届く範囲内にまで
来てるってことですね。
to be within range of my jutsu!
おっと　懐かしむのはあとぞ。
Oops! We'll have to
reminisce later!
それより連合も　お前たちにも
伝えておくことがある。
I have things I must relay
to you five and everyone else!
心して聞けい。
Listen to me carefully!
《もう少し
チャクラを取り戻しておくか。
I'll retrieve a little more chakra.
開花には時間が　かかりすぎる》
It's taking too long for it to bloom.
じゃあ　俺たちは
あの木の養分ってことですか…。
So we're just nourishment
for that tree?
忍とは
そんなものだったのですか？
That's what shinobi are?!
なら　どうやって　あんなのと…。
Then... how are we supposed to fight it?
あと１５分程度しか
ないってのに　そんなムチャな！
If there's only 15 minutes left,
it's crazy!
近づけもしないのに！
We can't even get close to it!
かといって
何もしなければ結局　同じ。
And yet, doing nothing will
yield the same result.
時間内に　あの木を切り倒すか→
We must either cut down that tree or
術者を倒すしかない。
defeat the caster within
the remaining time.
でも…。
But...
諦めるなと言ったはずぞ！！
I told you not to give up hope!
そうは言うが
あなたは　そもそも穢土転生だ！
That's what you say...
But you're a reanimated person
from the past!
もう死んだ過去の人だ！
だが　俺たちは生きてる。
Brought back to life!
We're still alive!
もう終わりだ…。
It's all... over...
こんなことなら
いっそ最初から…。
If it's going to end like this,
we shouldn't have gotten
started at all...
そうだ　そのままでいい。
That's right. Just stay like that.
悔やむことのない世界へ
連れていってやる。
I'll take you to a world where
there are no regrets.
（サスケ）ナルト　もう終わりか？
俺は行く！
Naruto, are you done?
Because I'm not.
行くぞ　重吾！
ああ。
Let's go, Jugo.
Yeah...
《これ！》
These are...
《感じる…　これって
ナルトの心が　私の術を通して…》
I can feel them,
these are Naruto's feelings...
coming through my jutsu.
《ナルト：あのとき　やっぱり
声かけときゃよかったって→
Back then...
I knew I should've called out to him.
あのあとで　何度も思ったんだ》
I thought about it over
and over afterwards.
《心が入ってくる》
His thoughts are flowing in.
《だから…》
That's why...
これは…。
This is...
こりゃ　あんときの…。
It's from that day...
俺は…。
I...
《後悔したくねえんだ。
I don't want to regret anything.
やっときゃよかったってよ》
I never want to think,
"I should have..."!
（ヒナタ）ナルト君…。
Naruto...
《それに
俺たちがやってきたこと全部…》
And...
I just can't make
everything we've done...
なかったことになんか
できねえんだよ！
up to this point meaningless!
サスケ！　俺も行くってばよ。
Sasuke!
I'm coming too!
うずまきナルト…。
Naruto Uzumaki...
《何度も何度も…》
Time and time again...
（九喇嘛）すまねえな
またチャクラもらっちまってよ。
Sorry to have to borrow
more chakra.
気にするな。
No worries!
《ミナト：ナルト　頼むよ》
Naruto, we're counting on you!
で　サスケ　お前→
Hey, Sasuke...
You realize that only Sage Jutsu
works on him, right?!
相手は仙術しか効かねえって
わかってんよな？
さっきのお前と一緒にするな。
Don't compare me to you.
香燐　ほら。
Look, Karin...
あれってさ
サスケの呪印模様だよね？
Isn't that... Sasuke's
Curse Mark patterning?
呪印の力は
なくなってたはずだろ。
The Curse Mark is supposed
to have lost its power...
そもそも
重吾の呪印は仙術の力。
Sage Power is the source
of Jugo's Curse Mark.
かつて　私の実験で→
And with Sasuke,
back when I experimented with
injecting Jugo's chakra into him,
その重吾のチャクラを注入されて→
すぐ呪印を解放したサスケ君だもの。
he immediately unleashed
the Curse Mark.
サスケ君の須佐能乎が→
So it's not surprising
for Sasuke's Susano'o
同じように
重吾のチャクラに適応しても→
to adapt to Jugo's chakra
in similar fashion.
何ら不思議じゃないわ。
つまり
仙術須佐能乎ってとこかしら。
In other words, you could call it
a Sage Jutsu Susano'o.
《扉間：うちはサスケか。
Sasuke Uchiha, huh?
かつてのマダラと
同じ可能性を見せる→
He shows the same potential
that Madara once did...
うちはの者よ》
You Uchiha...
うちも　あっちにまざろっかな。
Maybe I'll go over there too...
邪魔だって。　また刺されるよ。
You'll only be in the way.
You'll get stabbed again.
Bastard!
《そして　サスケ君　あなたの力は
この後ろの２人と違って→
And Sasuke...
Unlike these two in the back,
your power...
いや　私のどの実験体とも違って
まだまだ　こんな程度ではない。
Rather, unlike any of my experiments...
your power is nothing like theirs...
I can tell...
私には　わかるのよ。
私の生涯をかけ→
From my lifelong research
and the data I've gathered...
集めた情報から導き出せる
私の勘が　こう言うの。
my instincts tell me...
あなたは　いずれ
マダラを超えた忍になると》
that you'll one day be a shinobi
who surpasses Madara!
《そして　うずまきナルト　まるで
かつての兄者を見てるようだ。
And Naruto Uzumaki...
You remind me so much
of Elder Brother
when he was young.
バカで甘く　きれい事を
大声で口にするガキだ。
He's a foolish brat who spouts idealisms
at the top of their voice.
だが　なぜだか皆に好かれ
頼りたくなる》
And yet, everyone likes and
wants to depend on you.
狙え！
おう！
Aim!
Gotcha!
後悔は先に立たんぞ。
お前らの先には何もないがな！
It'll be too late for regrets,
you know.
Not that there's going to be
a future for either of you.
アイツら　ホントに
向かっていきやがった。
Those two really
went off to fight him?!
ああ　俺たちはどうする？
Yeah... so then what should
we all do?
五影様たちが来てから
聞いてみるか。
We can ask...
when the Five Kage get here.
そんなんでいいのか！？
Is that good enough?
((本当の夢の道へ行くまで
お前との戦いを楽しむさ。
I'm looking forward to
the battles we'll fight...
... up until the time I achieve
my true dream.
本当の夢ってなんだ？
What is your true dream?
俺たちの目指したものは
この里にあるんだろうが！
I thought everything we've aimed for
is here in this village!
お前は　見えないのさ。
更にこの先が…　先の夢が。
You just can't see it.
What's even further ahead...
dreams of the far future.
(だったら　その先の夢ってのを
教えてくれ))
Then tell me about your dreams
of the far future.
これは　初代様の記憶。
These are Lord First's memories?
FIRE
（柱間）先の夢…。
Dreams of the future...
FIRE LIGHTNING
FIRE LIGHTNING WIND
FIRE LIGHTNING WIND EARTH
FIRE LIGHTNING WIND EARTH WATER
((ここに　こうして
各五大国　初代五影が集い→
The fact that we were able
to convene this Five Kage Summit
with the first Kage of each
of the Five Nations...
五影会談ができること
本当に…。
truly fills me...
感謝する。
... with gratitude!
兄者　火の国木ノ葉隠れ
代表でもある火影が→
Elder Brother!
You are the Hokage, representing
the Hidden Leaf of the Land of Fire!
他の影相手に
簡単に頭を垂れるな！
A person like you, need not bow
to the other Kage!
だが　嬉しくてのう…。
But... I'm so happy!
火影殿　頭を上げろよ。
Lord Hokage, raise your head...
長たる者がよ
する行為じゃねえよ　それはよ。
That's not becoming of
a village leader...
確かに　火影殿の言われる
五影協定の趣旨に→
I did indeed come here to endorse
the gist of Lord Hokage's pact,
賛同するため　ここへ来たが
ただでサインするわけではない。
but I'm not just signing
anything for free.
あまり下手に出られると
何かあると勘ぐってしまうぞ。
If you behave too humbly,
you'll make us suspicious.
火影殿が集めた尾獣を
他里に分配するというのが→
Distributing the Tailed Beasts that
Lord Hokage has collected
to the other villages
協定へのサインの条件。
これは取り引きだ。
is the condition of signing the treaty.
This is a transaction,
not something to get emotional over.
感情だけに流されるものではない。
そのとおりだ。　尾獣は
バランスを考え分配するが→
Exactly, and we'll allocate
the Tailed Beasts based on power,
すべて買い取っていただく。
タダでも…。
but you will be acquiring them
for a price.
Not for free?
(黙れ！))
Shut up!
これが　最初の会談。
This was the very first summit!
（オオノキ）うむ。　これを期に
小さな争いは安定していく。
Yes, and it was what would lead
to the end of minor conflicts.
((我が里には
古くよりある寺の者たちが→
In our village,
a certain temple's disciples
have long been sealing away
a Tailed Beast.
尾獣を１匹封印してきた。
すでに　尾獣を持っている。
よって　もういらぬ。
Since we already have one,
we do not need another.
協定に協力するには
他里と違い→
Instead, we would like
an alternative compensation
それなりの見返りを求めるが
よろしいか？
for our collaboration in this pact.
Would that be acceptable?
何が望みだ？
What do you desire?
我らの国は　砂ばかりだ。
Our nation is completely
covered in sand.
よって　隣接する木ノ葉には→
Thus, we'd like the adjoining Leaf
尾獣の代わりに
豊かな土地をわけていただく。
to share arable land with us
instead of a Tailed Beast.
そして　他国には　尾獣を買う額の
３割をこちらにもいただきたい。
And the other nations to hand
over 30%
of your Tailed Beast
purchase price as well.
ふざけるな　風影！
Don't mess around, Kazekage!
なっ…。
すぎるぞ　風影殿！
What—?!
You overstep your bounds,
Lord Kazekage!
この条件を
のんでもらえなければ→
I won't sign on unless
all of you accept these terms!
協定には　サインしない。
砂漠ばかりの
生産性のない我が国で→
Mine is a desert-locked nation
with zero fertility!
４つの大国と
渡り合っていくには→
It's only natural to use my village's
Tailed Beast to full advantage
我が里の尾獣の存在を
大いに利用するのは当然。
in dealings with
the four other Great Nations!
我ら四国が手を組み　風の国を
叩くこともできるのだぞ。
We four nations could join up...
and defeat the Land of Wind...
今まで　確かに我々は
うまくいかないことだらけだった。
It's true that we've never
gotten along in the past...
我ら　おのおの同胞や一族を
守るためにやってきたことだ。
But we each did what we did
to protect our brethren and clans.
致しかたないときも
あったかもしれぬ。
There were, perhaps,
times when we had no other choice.
そして　今日　五国の協定が
うまくいったとしても→
And now, today, even if
our Five Nation Treaty comes to be...
それが　どこまで続くかも
守られるかも正直わからぬ。
I can't say how long it will last...
or if we can even hold to it.
だが　俺は　いつの日か
これから先　国は関係なく→
But I have this dream,
That sometime in the future...
忍が皆
協力し合い　助け合い→
There will come a day when
shinobi will collaborate,
心がひとつになる日がくると
夢みている。
and help each other, with one heart,
regardless of their affiliation.
それが　俺の思う　先の夢。
That is my...
My dream of the future.
今日は　その夢への
第一歩にしていただきたいのだ。
I ask you to take the first step
toward that dream today!
(どうか　どうか…))
So please, please, please, please...
頼む　我らの愛すべき子供たちよ！
I beg you!
All of my, our beloved children!
今こそ　我ら忍の痛みから
苦悩から　挫折から…。
Now is the time to
take all the pain,
the suffering, and frustration
we shinobi have endured...
紡いで見せてくれ！
我ら忍の本当の夢を！
and weave it into
Our true dream!
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
sugu wasurechatte dame da
It's not good that I'm so forgetful
uzukumattecha dame da
It's not good that I'm cowering
kizutsuitatte ana aitatte
Even if I'm wounded and pierced
massugu tatteirareruyou ni naritai
I want to be able to stand up straight
kimi ni makechai sou na kurai
Almost to the point of losing to you
kimi ni nayamasare sou da
Feeling like you might torment me
kimi ni kikoecha dame dame dame da
Not wanting you to hear me no, no, no
kimi ni nagasare sou na kurai
Swept away by you
kimi ni shiteyarare sou da
Taken in by you
kimi o omoccha dame dame dame da
I shouldn't love you no, no, no
Your past is filtering into me
through the others.
Naruto Uzumaki,
you are uniting everyone right now.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Your tempestuous life made you
into who you are.
美空ひばりです。
And your way of life has instilled
hope in everyone!
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Pursuing Hope."
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Let's go!
Let's cut down that tree!
２時間スペシャル！